<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[tomlock.me]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>tomlock.me</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:52:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:52:44 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Fish Slice]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>music/fish-slice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Music/Fish Slice.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:47:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Round Window]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>music/the-round-window.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Music/The Round Window.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:47:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[BrawlQuest]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="brawlquest1.png" src="/lib/media/brawlquest1.png"><br><br>BrawlQuest is an MMORPG centred on brawling and questing in a 2d environment. <br><br>Go, Lua, Love2D<br><br>This was a solo project for most of its lifetime sparked by a love of atmosphere in games like World of Warcraft and the "chatroom" feel of Club Penguin, two games that I played extensively as a child and pre-teen. <br>Whilst at University I built the game out to a full scale 2d MMORPG, then scrapped it literally weeks before release over fears it wouldn't be good enough. In fairness, it probably wouldn't have been.<br>In 2021 I received funding to work on the game full-time alongside of my <a data-href="FreshPlay" href="/projects/freshplay.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">FreshPlay</a> employees Dan, and we both spent 6 months building up to an early access release. I handled the server - rewritten in Go - and central game mechanics and business logic while Dan focused on the UI, along with frontend effects.<br>
<img alt="brawlquest2.png" src="/lib/media/brawlquest2.png"><br>We released it in 2022. Unfortunately, it didn't sell particularly well and issues stemming from the lack of a NA server prevented it from growing as we needed it to. <br>The game is still available, but development has ceased. You can watch a video breakdown of the game's development here: <a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E3O0EmvyrDA" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E3O0EmvyrDA</a><br><br>
<br>I love game development and if it was economically feasible I'd spend the rest of my life developing fun little games and growing communities
<br>Game development is not economically feasible if your focus is on developing fun little games and growing communities rather than marketing, marketing, monetisation and marketing
<br>Love2D is very fun for making small projects but a nightmare when you hit 20k+ lines of code
<br>Go is amazing!!!! 
]]></description><link>projects/brawlquest.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/BrawlQuest.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:43:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/brawlquest1.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib/media/brawlquest1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[FreshPlay]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>FreshPlay was a mobile development agency I started after leaving University in 2019.<br><br>Dart, Flutter, Go, Firebase, Supabase, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, TypeScript<br><br>When I finished university and returned home to my childhood bedroom in Frinton-On-Sea, I knew that I had exactly 1 year in which I could try and build something to provide a start to life for me and my fiancée. I'd worked at a mobile development agency ran by a couple of friends during my third year, and decided to give it a go myself.<br><img alt="fp1.png" src="/lib/media/fp1.png"><br>I started off on Fiverr building apps for pennies on the hour; e-commerce, social media, games etc. All for 5 USD (which was 4 USD after Fiverr's fees!!) My completed project list and 5* reviews amassed quickly and I was able to raise my prices substantially, until eventually having so many jobs on the go that I needed to expand. I hired my first employee 3 months after starting the business, and after 6 months we'd earned over $50,000.<br>
<img alt="fp3.png" src="/lib/media/fp3.png"><br>It was at this time that we decided to branch out to an office, and laterally enhance our offering my hiring an in-house designer and an additional developer. We also began acquiring clients outside of Fiverr and local to us; one of the many benefits that comes with being stuck into an office community.<br><img alt="fp2.png" src="/lib/media/fp2.png"><br>However, 3 years of quick turnarounds and constant crunch took their toll and our business model proved unfeasible. Work life balance was practically non-existent and I found myself in a constant state of stress. This had serious implications for my mental health - something I realised when it was too late to change our model. I stepped away in 2022 and sought regular 9-5 work. The business was continued by two of my colleagues but has since closed its doors.<br><br>
<br>I'm a very good mobile app developer
<br>I can be extremely organised and pro-active when using the right tools
<br>The mindset of the people you employ is as important as the quality of their output; if you're on different wavelengths work-wise things can be disastrous even if you're usually great friends 
<br>Sometimes it's important to step away from things that aren't working for you
]]></description><link>projects/freshplay.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/FreshPlay.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:41:34 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/fp1.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib/media/fp1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inhabit]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="InhabitLogo.png" src="/lib/media/inhabitlogo.png"><br><br>The "world's first" social habit tracking app<br><br>Dart, Flutter, Firebase, JavaScript<br><br>As my mental health was failing towards the end of my tenure with <a data-href="FreshPlay" href="/projects/freshplay.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">FreshPlay</a> I turned to the self-help community in an attempt to find an answer to the question of why I felt I was coming undone. This created some deep seated beliefs that both served and destroyed me.<br>
<img alt="Inhabit2.png" src="/lib/media/inhabit2.png"><br>
I convinced myself that the answer was in productivity hacking, and that any shortcoming was a result of a poor system. I began to see myself as a machine that turned tasks into successes (or failures) and that there was no wiggle room for any alternative. <br>Inhabit is a habit tracking app that beats you over the head with accountability signals. You can setup your daily tasks and are given a streak of how many days in a row you've completed that task - easy - but you can also setup "rooms" that multiple people exist in all striving to complete the same habits. You can see who has completed which habits that day, you can see what streak each person is on and you can chat about/show off your progress in the chat room.<br>
<img alt="Inhabit1.png" src="/lib/media/inhabit1.png"><br>
There's also a "news" style section that attempts to teach the tenets of self-discipline and mental toughness in short inspirational posts and quotes. <br>Inhabit is a beautiful app, designed mostly by I<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.linkedin.com/in/isismawdi/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/isismawdi/" target="_blank">sis Mawdsley-Daiz</a> with the occasional addition from myself during implementation. It's a very functional app, and serves its purpose well.<br>The only issue is that I don't believe in the principles its foundation is built upon. That's a bit of problem, isn't it?<br>I'm working on a new version of Inhabit that takes a gentler approach; I believe that productivity systems are excellent tools and that atomic-style habits are superb when employed correctly... but that everyone needs something slightly different and that focusing entirely on productivity creates more problems than it solves. <br><br>
<br>Getting stuff from conception to release is hard, but I did it!
<br>Isis is a fantastic designer, and the quality of any given project can be greatly enhanced by utilising the right people at the right time
<br>A lot of self-help content is nonsense, and basing your whole life around those principles will utterly destroy your mental frame
]]></description><link>projects/inhabit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Projects/Inhabit.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:42:15 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/inhabitlogo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib/media/inhabitlogo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hi there!]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>My name's Tom. I'm a 26 year old developer from Clacton-On-Sea in Essex. Currently I work as Senior Mobile Developer at OpenAdvice, a financial technology startup making great financial planning accessible to all. I'm also a content creator, a musician, husband, father and ITFC supporter.<br>This website has been created using Obsidian, because I didn't have a website/the time to make a proper one. It feels sort of like documentation, and I like the idea of that. This is the documentation associated with me, Tom. This is the Tom documentation. <br>I'll post and expand on projects and blogs and other things here. <br><br>Check out the projects folder on the left where you can learn about the different things I've been involved in. The list is, of course, not exhaustive and I will add to it as and when I find the time.<br><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/Pebsie" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/Pebsie" target="_blank">GitHub</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/@PebsieTTV" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/@PebsieTTV" target="_blank">YouTube</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://twitter.com/PebsieTTV" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/PebsieTTV" target="_blank">Twitter</a>]]></description><link>hi-there!.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Hi there!.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 12:47:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>